a five kilogram mass placed at the
origin
and a nine kilogram mass is placed at x
equals two meters where is the center of
mass
so let's draw a picture
so here's the five kilogram mass
and this is going to be the 9 kilogram
mass
so this is at position 0
with respect to the origin
and this is at x equals two
so where do you think the center of mass
is going to be located
now it has to be somewhere between the
five and the nine kilogram mass
is it going to be closer to the five
kilogram mass or the nine kilogram mass
what would you say
the center of mass is going to be closer
to the more massive object so it should
be somewhere between one and two
to calculate it you can use this
equation
it's the mass times the position
of each particle
is the sum of those values divided by
the total mass
so in this example m1
is 5
and the position of m1
is 0.
the second mass is 9
and is positioned on the x-axis
is two
and then we need to divide it by the
total mass
so five times zero is zero
nine times two is eighteen
and five plus nine is fourteen
so it's going to be 18 divided by 14
which turns out to be about 1.29
on the x-axis
so that's the position of the center of
mass
and as you can see it's closer to the
nine kilogram mass
as opposed to the five kilogram mass
it's between one and two
an eight kilogram mass is placed at y
equals three where should a 10 kilogram
mass be placed along the y axis
so that the center of mass will be
located at y equals 4.5
well let's draw a picture
so this is the x-axis
and this is the y-axis
so at position 3
we have the 8 kilogram mass
and that 4.5
is where we want the center of mass to
be
so therefore we have to place the 10
kilogram mass
above the center of mass
so that
the center of mass will be located at
4.5
the question is exactly where on the
y-axis do we need to place it
so we could use this formula
the center of mass along the y-axis is
going to be
m1 y1
plus m2 y2
divided by the total mass m1 plus m2
so we have this value ready it's 4.5
mass 1 is 8 and it's located at position
3.
mass 2 is 10
and we're looking for its location
and the total mass is going to be 8 plus
10 or 18.
so we have 4.5 is equal to 8 times 3
which is 24
and 8 plus 10 is 18.
now let's cross multiply
so we have 4.5
times 18 which is 81
and that's going to be equal to 24
plus 10 y2
so now let's subtract both sides by 24.
81 minus 24
is 57 so 57 is equal to 10 y2
and then let's divide both sides by 10.
so the position of the second mass
should be at 5.7 meters
if we want the center of mass to be at
four point five
number three
the positions of masses
four kilogram six seven and ten
kilograms
are zero zero four zero zero five
and
five six
determine the position of the center of
mass of the system
so first let's draw a picture
so the first mass the four kilogram mass
that's located at the origin
then we have another mass
the six kilogram mass which is
located at position four
so this is four meters here
and then there's another one at zero
five
so that's the
seven kilogram mass
and then we have another one that's
located at 5 comma 6 which should be
somewhere in this region so that's the
10 kilogram mass
so with this information
how can we determine the position of the
center of mass of this entire system
so chances are if we had to estimate it
should be somewhere
between
somewhere in this region because
the majority of the mass
is close to the 10 kilogram mass
so it should be somewhere in the middle
of these four masses
so how do we go about calculating
the center of mass
for one thing
we need to take it one step at a time
let's calculate
the x-coordinate of the center of mass
so because there are four masses it's
going to be m1 x1
plus m2 x2
and then m3 x3
plus
m4 x4
divided by the total mass
so the first mass the four kilogram mass
is at a position of zero along the
x-axis so this is going to be four times
zero
the second mass
is located at x equals four
so that's going to be six times four
and the third mass the 70 kilogram mass
that's at a
an x value of zero
and then the last one the 10 kilogram
mass
it has an x value of five
and then let's divide it by the total
mass so that's four plus six plus seven
plus ten
so these two they're gonna disappear
they don't have any value
six times four is twenty-four
and ten times five is fifty
now four plus six is ten plus another
ten that's twenty
plus seven so that's twenty seven
and twenty four plus fifty
is seventy four
so seventy four divided by 27
is 2.74
so that's the x coordinate
of the center of mass
now let's do the same for the
y-coordinate
so it's going to be m1 y1
plus
m2 y2
and then you get the picture
now let's divide by the total mass
so mass 1 which is 4 kilograms
is located at y equals 0.
the second mass m2 is six kilograms
and the y value is at zero as well
the third one the seven kilogram mass
is located at y equals five
and the last one
is located at y equals six
and then divided by the same total mass
so we're going to have seven times five
which is 35
and then 10 times 6
is 60
and we know this is 27
35 plus 60 that's 95
so 95 divided by 27
is about 3.5
1 9.
so that's the y coordinate of the center
of mass
so that's it for this problem
a 10 meter long 4 000 kilogram truck
has its center of mass 4 meters behind
the front of the truck
where should a 1400 kilogram load be
placed
so that the center of mass
will be right in the middle of the truck
so let's draw a truck
okay my drawing's not perfect but
you get the picture
so we're going to say
this is the front so that's going to be
position 0
and this is 10 meters because
the truck is 10 meters long
now the center of mass of the truck
is 4 meters behind the truck so that's
going to be at position 4.
we want to place a load
somewhere in the back of the truck
so that we can move the center of mass
from position four
to position five
that's the goal of the problem
so where should we place the 1400
kilogram load
to move the center of mass from four to
five
so keep this in mind the blue dot
represents the center of mass of the
truck alone
the green dot
is the center of mass of the truck and
the load combined
so in order to determine where we should
place the load
we need to use this equation
the center of mass
of the truck and a load is equal to the
mass of the truck
times the center of mass of the truck
plus the mass of the load
times the position
of where the load is located divided by
the total mass
so the center of mass of the system
is five that's where we want it to be
the mass of the truck is four thousand
kilograms
and the center of mass of the truck
is at position four
the mass of the load is 1400 and we got
to find out where to place it
so that the center of mass changes from
four to five
and the total mass is going to be four
thousand
plus fourteen hundred
so that's
five thousand four hundred now let's
cross multiply so five times fifty four
hundred
is twenty seven thousand
so that's equal to four thousand times
four
which is sixteen thousand plus fourteen
hundred x two
so now let's subtract both sides by this
number
so twenty seven thousand minus sixteen
thousand
is eleven thousand
and so that's equal to fourteen hundred
times x two
so now let's divide both sides by
fourteen hundred
eleven thousand divided by fourteen
hundred
is equal to seven point eight six meters
so that's where we need to place the
1400 kilogram load
in order to move the center of mass from
four to five
so it should be somewhere
around this region it's still relatively
close to the back of the truck
but it's not all the way at the back
you